Finding Aid for the James W. Cocke Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
James W. Cocke Collection
1954-1957
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0567
.07 linear feet
Biography/History
James W. Cocke, a Nashville native, was a career military man with the United States Army, and attained the rank of Lieutenant Colonel. He attended Hume-Fogg High School, Tennessee Polytechnic Institute, and the University of Maryland. He served in European Campaign during World War II, and was a Professor of Military Science and Tactics over the Army ROTC at Vanderbilt University from 1954-1957. He was then reassigned to the Far East Command.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains 33 items in seven file folders, related to the Army ROTC at Vanderbilt University, and includes certificates, correspondence, a faculty appointment list, newspaper clippings, photographs, and a publication.
- Certificates – (2)
  - The National Society of Pershing Rifles, February 1956
  - Department of the Army – Extract Notice, March 1, 1957
- Correspondence – (4)
  - from Harvie Branscomb, September 3, 1954
  - from C. M Sarratt, September 10, 1954
  - from Murray M. Johnson, May 16, 1955
  - from Harvie Branscomb, December 28, 1955
- Faculty Appointment – (1)
  - College of Arts and Science – New Faculty, September 20, 1954
- Journal – (1)
  - “The ROTC Journal”, November 1955
- Newspaper Clippings – (8)
  - May 22, 1955
  - December 15, 1955
  - April 17, 1956
  - May 24, 1957
  - No dated – (4)
- Photographs – Digital Copies – (16)
- Photographs – Prints – (4)